Statement versus question intonation. You may have learned at some point that
questions have a rising intonation. They do, but usually a question will step
upward until the very end where it takes one quick little downward step. A question
rises a little higher than a statement with the same intonation pattern. Here's
my car. Where's my car? Emotional or rhetorical question intonation. If you
know that your car is parked outside, however, and someone doesn't see it and
ask you where it is, you might think that it has been stolen, and your emotion will
show in your intonation as you repeat the question. As your feelings rise in an
emotional situation, your intonation rises up along with them. Where's my car? Why?
Is it gone?